we were oppressed from remembering.
So my grandma shared like when they were in Palestine,
if they even heard you singing like Palestinian songs
of Nanak or anything, like they would arrest you.
Like they don't even want you to remember
or to talk about what happens.
I think for a lot of us who are listening
and know even like a basic history
of black people coming to America,
this is the methodology of colonization.
It is the erasing of identity.
It wasn't that they just killed Native Americans
when they came here.
The children of Native Americans were then put in schools
to unlearn their Native American heritage.
And they were taught to, like you just said,
unlearn their traditions and be assimilated
into American society.
The same thing was done with Aborigines in Australia.
If you see the movie Rabbit Proof Fence,
they took the children from their parents
and then they start trying to marry the children off
to white Australians because they're literally trying
to cleanse the ethnicity.
It's genocide is what it is.